<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-11-10T13:36:36+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lost Letters</title><subtitle>A personal site home to the Afternoon Tea Pixel Club</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The End of an Era: 3 Years of D&amp;amp;D 5E</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/11/06/three-yrs-dnd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The End of an Era: 3 Years of D&amp;amp;D 5E" /><published>2023-11-06T22:56:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-11-06T22:56:00+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/11/06/three-yrs-dnd</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/11/06/three-yrs-dnd.html"><![CDATA[<p>The final multi-boss battle of our 86-session, three-year D&amp;D fifth edition campaign was as stressful and exhilarating as we could have hoped. Every party member was on point, scouring their 12th level character sheets to pull out every possible trick we had up our sleeves.<!--excerpt--> Our cleric cast Twilight Sanctuary early on to give us all bonus HP throughout the battle. We ended up all rolling very close to max for bonus HP every round, which always came in clutch. Our monk and barbarian exchanged massive blows with our enemies, a storm giant and an eldritch knight. Shortly after defeating the storm giant, the monk and barbarian went down along with our cleric. As the last party member standing with single digit HP and no spell slots left, my only option was to try eldritch blasting the remaining knight because I was out of spell slots. Somehow, the dice blessed me, enabling me to hit the knight with an AC of 21 and doing nearly max damage on two blasts needed to end the battle. I would have been more stressed if I wasn’t used to nearly every major battle of ours coming down to the wire just like this. We couldn’t have asked for a more cinematic finish to our bloody quest. Our DM wrapped the session by noting that our final session in two weeks would be an RP-heavy epilogue to send off our characters and conclude the campaign. I fully expect to tear up as we say goodbye to our now 13th level characters, who have grown with us since March 30th, 2020. 
<br />
<br />
I am so grateful that our virtual table of five has persisted despite the fact that two folks independently moved internationally three times during the campaign, and we now span Japan and US West coast time zones. It’s been the most surprisingly successful way for me to stay in touch with these friends who were all at one point living in the same city as me. I’m excited to continue adventuring with these folks as we switch to using the Star Wars: Edge of the Empire system in 2024 for our next campaign. I’ve already started crafting my character for this new setting: 
<br />
<br />
A young retired inventor who is living in a house boat-like space ship suddenly loses their retirement funds and has to bring on renters and do odd jobs to make ends meet. Before they retired, they invented something that ended up being used to further subjugate lower classes of society, which the retiree now finds themselves a part of. Being subjected to the ill-effects of their invention motivates them to work towards the expensive endeavor of researching and developing a counter invention to right the wrongs of their original one. 
<br />
<br />
I like that this character has both a short-term goal (keep the roof over their head) and long-term goal (redemption) with ample plot hooks (how they lost their retirement funds as well as the specifics of the invention are being left up to the DM). I still haven’t read the Core Rulebook yet, so the species, name, and other specifics are yet to be determined, but there is interest amongst the group to play an oops all droids party with one token organic friend (my partner’s character), so I’ll likely be a bot for this game. I’m excited to work out the details and hopefully add a more detailed writeup to my OCs page in the future. In the meantime, if you have any actual play recommendations for either Edge of the Empire campaigns or one-shots, please reach out. Thanks!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="fun" /><category term="ttrpgs" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The final multi-boss battle of our 86-session, three-year D&amp;D fifth edition campaign was as stressful and exhilarating as we could have hoped. Every party member was on point, scouring their 12th level character sheets to pull out every possible trick we had up our sleeves.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4-day Tokyo Itinerary for First Time Visitors (vegan-friendly)</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/11/01/tokyo-itinerary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4-day Tokyo Itinerary for First Time Visitors (vegan-friendly)" /><published>2023-11-01T12:19:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-11-01T12:19:00+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/11/01/tokyo-itinerary</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/11/01/tokyo-itinerary.html"><![CDATA[<p><b>CW: food mention (vegan)</b>
<br />
<br />
After more than four years of living in Japan, I finally got my first visitors! My dad and step-mom came out to see me and Japan for the first time. There was so much I wanted to show them to give a holistic sense of Tokyo, but also a slice of my life that’s so different from their own, living in the US. I wanted to share the itinerary in case some stranger on the internet needs to accommodate a vegan diet while visiting Tokyo for the first time.<!--excerpt-->
<br />
<br />
<b>Day 1 | Sat, Oct 28 | 17,847 steps</b>
<img src="/graphics/blog/skytree.jpg" alt="Tokyo sky tree lit up in blue with a full moon near the top left of it. Lights from the city are reflected in the Sumida River with a dinner cruise boat drifting by" title="Tokyo Sky Tree over the Sumida River" style="width: 30%; padding: 1em 0 0 1em;" align="right" />
<br />
After a train ride from Haneda Airport in the early afternoon, Asakusa’s Sensoji Temple and Kappabashi (kitchenware shopping street) area left great first impressions, and the neighborhood proved to be a good hotel location for these first-time tourists. They loved hunting for organic-looking raku pottery, getting graphic t-shirts at a larger-than-average Uniqlo store, and hitting up the 24/7 Don Quijote for souvenirs. It was cute to watch them rack up bags of KitKats and other knickknacks as they explained whose stockings would get what for Christmas. It made me just a bit sad, knowing that I have been and will continue to miss out on this tradition from their lives on other side of the world. We ended the night walking along the Sumida River after getting dinner at <a target="_blank" href="https://gonpachi.jp/asakusa/">Gonpatchi</a>, which has a dedicated vegan menu. We stumbled across a local festival complete with a donut of dancers that encircled the elevated live music performers. All of this was illuminated by electric lanterns under the light of a full moon at the foot of Tokyo’s Sky Tree tower. It felt like the city was putting on its best face just for us, but that’s really what Tokyo is like nearly year-round.
<br />
<br />
<b>Day 2 | Sun, Oct 29 | 20,853 steps</b>
<br />
This day, I planned to go to Wired Bon Bon in Shinjuku for mont blanc (sweet chestnut puree) parfaits, sweeping views of the city from the Tokyo Metropolitan Government Building, as well as a tour of Shinjuku Gyoen, but a slight sprinkle of rain deterred us from the last stop. Instead, we headed to Shimokitazawa for second-hand shopping and some Thai food at <a target="_blank" href="https://titchai.tokyo/">Titchai</a> (they’ll veganize their menu for you). My dad loved the food and vibes of such a small and charming dinner spot, and my step-mom appreciated that we weren’t only having Japanese food on the trip because Japanese food is an undesirable leap from her usual diet of mostly salads and other American fare. Despite admonishments from the local government, we did explore Shibuya on Halloweekend because it was most convenient for their train transfer back to their hotel. I was honestly impressed at how the government managed to suppress the Halloween festivities with cops with loud speakers, harassing any groups larger than four people. The fun vibe on the street of Halloweens past was totally missing, but it was so nice to show my family around shops and malls like LoFT and PARCO without crowds.
<br />
<br />
<b>Day 3 | Mon, Oct 30 | 19,372 steps</b>
<br />
We started the day off with lunch at <a target="_blank" href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/nA6h12CVnYHT3FYY8">Cosme Kitchen Adaption</a> in Shibuya (vegan items are labeled in English on their menu) to get some sorely missed leaves and vegetables into the stomach of my step-mom, then we walked through Miyashita Park, Cat Street, and Omotesando. I then took them to see my apartment and local neighborhood, finishing the night off with udon and dessert. By this point, they were sore, exhausted, and getting sick of the endless malls of Tokyo, fully understanding that shopping is an unofficial national pastime. They longed for more nature, so we decided to head to Kamakura the next day instead of checking out Yanaka Ginza (cat-themed shopping street), Nezu Shrine, and Ueno.
<br />
<br />
<b>Day 4 | Tue, Oct 31 | 13,348 steps</b>
<img src="/graphics/blog/buddha.jpg" alt="An oxidized bronze Buddha statue in a sitting meditation ￼position. The sky behind the statue is overcast, and there are also green and yellowing trees. " title="Kamakura Daibutsu" style="width: 30%; padding: 1em 1em 0 0;" align="left" />
<br />
After I checked my family into their next hotel, I navigated us by train to Kamakura to see the second largest bronze Buddha in Japan at Kotoku-in as well as their first bamboo garden at Hokokuji Temple. They were rejuvenated by more natural sights, and I was simply delighted that we actually could actually get seats on the <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enoshima_Electric_Railway">Eno-den (江ノ電) train</a> without the usual hoards of hot, sticky tourists, shoving their way into the most overstuffed train I’ve ever had the displeasure of riding. For lunch, we had decent thai food with a third story view of the beach at <a target="_blank" href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/HMejfsnzezTHWJPL8">タイ料理 889</a> (they’ll veganize their menu for you), then we had to book it to the bamboo grove because they close at 16:00. Despite being so much smaller than I remembered, the bamboo forest left my step-mom speechless, so I would definitely recommend this for nature lovers who have never been to a bamboo forest before. Had I recalled how small it was beforehand, we probably would have skipped it, but I’m glad we didn’t. After some very careful coaching and examination of the Google Maps train directions, I let them navigate their own way back to their hotel with not much more than metro cards and a prayer. Thankfully, they made it without too much trouble, and I feel relieved that they’re a bit more proficient with navigating than before, especially as they’re about to be an actual paid tour guide’s responsibility for the next two weeks.
<br />
<img src="/graphics/blog/bamboo.jpg" alt="A white sky peaks through the leaves of bamboo stalks that rise up from all around" title="bamboo forest" style="width: 100%; padding: 1em 0; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" />
This was exhausting and yet not exhaustive of all that I wanted to show them, but I’m happy we covered so much ground in the limited amount of time we had. It felt empowering being able to order food for them in Japanese and handle all things related to the metro, even if I was just taking care of the most routine things. Most days, I live acutely aware of the limit of my Japanese ability, but, during these four days, I was consistently impressed with myself, knowing that I wouldn’t have been this proficient, confident, nor flexible with planning this trip on the fly without the past four years of experience. It’s rare I get to see myself in such a positive light even if I had to remind them for the hundredth time that day that I can’t read the kanji calligraphy on some random scroll, t-shirt, sign, or stone.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="fun" /><category term="travel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CW: food mention (vegan) After more than four years of living in Japan, I finally got my first visitors! My dad and step-mom came out to see me and Japan for the first time. There was so much I wanted to show them to give a holistic sense of Tokyo, but also a slice of my life that’s so different from their own, living in the US. I wanted to share the itinerary in case some stranger on the internet needs to accommodate a vegan diet while visiting Tokyo for the first time.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One Year on Neocities</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/18/one-year-neocities.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Year on Neocities" /><published>2023-10-18T17:50:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-10-18T17:50:00+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/18/one-year-neocities</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/18/one-year-neocities.html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember when I just created my Neocities account on October 28 last year. I was brimming with inspiration from sites across the yesterweb (it still existed at that time). At first, all I wanted to do was create a pink site with a pixel toybox and enjoy the thrill of having bite-sized cuteness on my page. However, when it came to actually creating literally anything else of substance, I’ll never forget my girlfriend encouraging me to create something that only <i>I</i> could. That’s been the guiding principle behind Lost Letters ever since.<!--excerpt-->
<br />
<br />
As a non-technical amateur who was returning to web development for the first time in over a decade, there was so much to learn. I tried to use my beginner lens to helpfully document the <a href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2022/11/02/jekyll">process of creating a site using Jekyll and GitHub for fellow beginners</a>. Several other <a href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/tag/webmastery/">webmastery blog posts</a> were similarly inspired. If I’m trying to figure something out, I write the documentation I wish I had while going through the process. I encourage others to do the same, especially if you’re completely new to it.
<br />
<br />
Another major undertaking that was something only I could create and share was <a href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/quilt/">my own personal experience and connection to the quilting bee</a>. It’s not even on my top 5 most visited pages, but I poured my soul into creating that shrine, spending hours on the internet archive; diving back into cherished bookmarks that I could never quite get myself to delete; and reconnecting with the former queen and staff bees to get as many files as I could. It was the first page I was truly proud of on this site.
<br />
<br />
While nostalgia is well and good, I didn’t want to stop there. I wanted to revive some of the magic of the old web, so my next project was launching the <a href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/afternoontea/">Afternoon Tea Pixel Club</a>. I’ve been so absolutely blown away by its reception across the small web. Technically, it launched on November 7, 2022, so I’ll probably throw a mini tea party celebration once we actually hit one year, but I can’t believe I’ve received 62 submissions as of the day I’m writing this. Every single time someone sends in a cup they made, it makes my day. Please don’t stop.
<br />
<br />
Having social aspects to web development has been the biggest reason why I was able to stick with this hobby for a whole year. I love being able to follow inspiring sites across neocities, connect with and help plan events for fellow web devs through the amazing <a target="_blank_" href="https://32bit.cafe/">32-bit.cafe community</a> (especially after the implosion of the yesterweb), and keep up with blog posts within and beyond neocities for free with RSS. Every day, my world is expanded and enriched by the many folks crafting the small web, sharing their knowledge, interests, and hobbies. Through this little web dev endeavor of mine and the community that surrounds it, I’ve constantly been taught that I don’t know what I’m capable of until I try. Things are almost always completely opaque at the start, but so much is possible when I approach things and just say, “let’s just try and figure this out,” instead of shutting the door on myself and closing off any potential for me to grow. I’m so grateful that I had and continue to have the courage to try, and I hope you do too as a fellow person on the small web.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reflection" /><category term="fun" /><category term="webmastery" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I remember when I just created my Neocities account on October 28 last year. I was brimming with inspiration from sites across the yesterweb (it still existed at that time). At first, all I wanted to do was create a pink site with a pixel toybox and enjoy the thrill of having bite-sized cuteness on my page. However, when it came to actually creating literally anything else of substance, I’ll never forget my girlfriend encouraging me to create something that only I could. That’s been the guiding principle behind Lost Letters ever since.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Responsive Take on a Classic 3-Column Layout</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/14/new-layout.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Responsive Take on a Classic 3-Column Layout" /><published>2023-10-14T07:37:34+09:00</published><updated>2023-10-14T07:37:34+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/14/new-layout</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/14/new-layout.html"><![CDATA[<p>I coded this new layout over two days, listening to Pain Hasn’t Hit Me by The Crane almost exclusively. It reminded me of listening to Burning by The Whitest Boy Alive in high school, browsing tumblrs of girls who were definitely cooler than me. Fitting with that nostalgia, I wanted to create a desktop layout that I don’t see often anymore: the classic “holy grail” 3-column layout.<!--excerpt--> I immediately went to <a target="_blank" href="https://matthewjamestaylor.com/holy-grail-layout">Matthew James Taylor’s website</a> as it offers the bare bones code for literally any layout you could possibly want. As a bonus, they’re all responsive for mobile, and he offers many different ways to approach the layouts using CSS grid, flex, or whatever you’re comfortable with. There are so many sites on Neocities that could be mobile-friendly, and this is such an easy way to go about that. I hope more folks learn from this incredible resource.
<br />
<br />
Once I had the code for my site structure, I wanted to add a theme switcher for Halloween. This is done easily just by switching out whatever you want to customize in your main CSS file by swapping in variables and having those defined in separate style sheets that some JS can point to. I followed <a target="_blank" href="https://www.studytonight.com/post/build-a-theme-switcher-for-your-website-with-javascript">this very easy tutorial</a> that provided all the code snippets needed, then I got busy, committing as many CSS crimes as I wanted. The entire effort took about two days, but the majority of that was spent tweaking the CSS to figure out fun combinations that worked well together and then leaving it alone for a while so I could view it with fresh eyes. One of the really helpful resources I used to develop cohesive color schemes for each layout was <a target="_blank" href="https://colorffy.com/css-generator">colorffy’s CSS / SCSS color variables generator</a>. You just specify a HEX code for a color you like, and it spits out a family of related shades, which you can then evaluate to ensure you’ve got the right contrast ratios for your site.
<br />
<br />
Now that the coding is done, I can focus on creating Halloween adoptables for the <a target="_blank" href="https://tilde.32bit.cafe/~slug/events/halloween-2023/">32-bit cafe Halloween Event</a> (join us if you’re also 18+ y/o). You can get an early preview of some of the pixels I’ve made for the event on my <a href="/toybox/#halloween-23">toybox page</a>. I’m particularly proud of my submission for the Fizzy Vendor club since animating fire took a couple tried before I didn’t hate the result. I can’t wait to see everyone’s creations. I really hope folks are busy, creating loads of pixel art, playlists, web pages, and more for this event. I can’t believe Halloween is just 17 days away! 🎃</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="webmastery" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I coded this new layout over two days, listening to Pain Hasn’t Hit Me by The Crane almost exclusively. It reminded me of listening to Burning by The Whitest Boy Alive in high school, browsing tumblrs of girls who were definitely cooler than me. Fitting with that nostalgia, I wanted to create a desktop layout that I don’t see often anymore: the classic “holy grail” 3-column layout.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to become “That Girl” as a depressed thirty-year-old</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/09/that-girl-okr.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to become “That Girl” as a depressed thirty-year-old" /><published>2023-10-09T07:37:34+09:00</published><updated>2023-10-09T07:37:34+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/09/that-girl-okr</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/09/that-girl-okr.html"><![CDATA[<p>This past week, I officially started my long-term sick leave from work. The healing and inner work I need to do during this leave is uncharted territory for me, so, in addition to getting professional, qualified help, I’ve tried to formulate a daily routine to aid my recovery and avoid stagnating in overwhelm.<!--excerpt--> Since I can’t turn off my work-pilled brain, I accidentally created an OKR (<i>inexcusable, I know</i>) for what I want to achieve during my sick leave: 
<br />
<br />
Get back to a holistically healthy state by the end of the year <em>as measured by</em></p>
<ol>
	<li>consistently exercising</li>
	<li>mindfully eating anytime I eat (instead of frantically regulating my emotions with food)</li>
	<li>consistently engaging with activities/hobbies that I enjoy</li>
</ol>
<p><br />
To achieve these key results, I’m cultivating the following daily habits:</p>
<ul>
	<li><b>Journal</b> - set my intention for the day, then craft and visualize my daily plan by answering the prompt: how do I want to feel physically and mentally today, and what actions can I add to my day to help with this? Write until I've filled at least one A6 page.</li>
	<li><b>Meditate</b> - practice mindfulness by use my subscription to headspace to complete at least one meditation of any duration.</li>
	<li><b>Exercise</b> - alternate between workout days (30+ mins of running, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5JmWguyvu7Y&amp;list=PLXFVbuJY5qGpFzJ7i-AhREynwF7VdUFUy">lifting based on research meta-analyses</a>, TRX) and low-intensity steady state cardio days (30+ mins of walking) to ensure I take consistent rest and don't trigger an all-or-nothing mentality.</li>
	<li><b>Physical Therapy</b> - complete the sets and reps assigned to me by my podiatrist to avoid re-injury that would limit/prohibit daily exercise.</li>
	<li><b>Study</b> - work through the <a target="_blank" href="https://itsryannnicole.com/hfm">Hunger and Fullness Masterclass by Ryann Nicole</a>; rinse and repeat. </li>
</ul>
<p><br />
Completing that list everyday this past week took a lot of will power, but it was made easier by actually doing even more. The following habits helped me build momentum, enabling me to psych myself up to tackle the harder things on the previous list:</p>
<ul>
	<li><b>Read for fun</b> - any book, any duration, any format. Read through my <a target="_blank" href="https://cutie.city/@lostletters/111160178171394271">anti-capitalist and union/collective bargaining book list</a>. Track it with <a target="_blank" href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/profile/lostletters">The Story Graph</a>. </li>
<li><b>Skin care routine</b> - this is just an easy self-care win as I tend to give up on my skin when I'm depressed. I looked into what <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=loUjg47Osoc">dermatologists recommend to reduce pores</a>, then specifically sought out products for my skin type. It's only been three weeks, but I'm already seeing an improvement, so I've got a positive feedback cycle going now. </li>
</ul>
<p><br />
Echoing my past post on my health, it’s easy to get overwhelmed and think that things are actually getting worse, but I don’t believe that. Although I do have more diagnoses now than ever before, I’m clearer than ever on what I want to treat and how to go about that. I’ve learned how to avoid setting unhealthy and unreasonable goals, and my capacity to achieve them is greater than ever thanks to the treatments I’m already receiving. It’s been a month since my post on learned helplessness, and it’s exciting to see how much agency I’ve reclaimed just by shifting my mindset since then. Here’s to happier and healthier futures! 🥂</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="self-reflection" /><category term="adulting" /><category term="goals" /><category term="mental-health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This past week, I officially started my long-term sick leave from work. The healing and inner work I need to do during this leave is uncharted territory for me, so, in addition to getting professional, qualified help, I’ve tried to formulate a daily routine to aid my recovery and avoid stagnating in overwhelm.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">September Recap &amp;amp; October Habits</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/01/oct-habits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="September Recap &amp;amp; October Habits" /><published>2023-10-01T19:37:34+09:00</published><updated>2023-10-01T19:37:34+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/01/oct-habits</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/10/01/oct-habits.html"><![CDATA[<p>September was filled with significant strides in health improvement, but, after nearly 8 years of working, I’ve finally committed to taking my first health-related leave of absence from work.<!--excerpt--> This past month, I’ve made huge strides in recognizing and addressing my disordered eating; I’ve worked with my doctor to further adjust my bipolar medication; and I’ve secured the strongest support systems I’ve ever had to continue my health management journey. It has been frustrating to see my hobbies like web development, knitting, journaling, and running take a backseat this month, but I really had to focus on my health. Now that I won’t be working for a while, I hope that I can feel safe and inspired to engage with some hobbies once more.
<br />
<br />
Looking ahead to October, I’m a little nervous by having just so much free time. As a person with ADHD, I need structure to my days. I hate not having a plan because it means that my indecision will paralyze me in bed until I feel like I’ve wasted the day. To avoid that, I have several new habits I’d like to integrate into my daily routine to get me out of bed and build some momentum.
<br />
<br />
For the past 7 days, I’ve completed my morning pages, a practice from The Artist’s Way by Julia Cameron (I don’t recommend the book, but the practice is good). Technically, my “morning pages” are more like a single A6 page, but I’m proud of my consistency regardless. Getting out of bed to brain dump when my head is relatively empty is frictionless. It ensures I get out of bed shortly after waking up, and it makes me use stationery that would otherwise go to waste, so I want to keep up this rewarding habit through the month of October at least. 
<br />
<br />
In terms of new habits, I want to actually finish one of those monthly fitness calendars published by the likes of <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIJwWYOfsCfz6PjxbONYXSg">Blogilates</a> or <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/@yogawithadriene">Yoga with Adriene</a>. I chose Adriene’s <a target="_blank" href="https://yogawithadriene.com/calendar/">October yoga calendar</a> because I still plan on running, lifting, or using my TRX daily for workouts and alternating with walking on recovery days to improve my emotional regulation. I need to dedicate myself to stretching not only to improve my plantar fasciitis, but also to prevent any injury from the increased movement. I foresee this being difficult at the end of the month when my dad and stepmom visit for three days, but even if I’m not perfect, getting in any yoga at all will be a huge achievement.
<br />
<br />
The last daily habit that I hope to follow through with is using headspace to meditate. I’ve got a free subscription through work, and I could always use more tools to help with anxiety management, especially since finding a decent therapist in Japan is a joke. Even if I only sit down for 5 minutes to mediate like today, I’ll be happy with that.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-recap" /><category term="resolutions" /><category term="mental-health" /><category term="health" /><category term="self-reflection" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[September was filled with significant strides in health improvement, but, after nearly 8 years of working, I’ve finally committed to taking my first health-related leave of absence from work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weekly Recap: Sept 18 - 24</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/25/weekly-recap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weekly Recap: Sept 18 - 24" /><published>2023-09-25T20:24:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T20:24:00+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/25/weekly-recap</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/25/weekly-recap.html"><![CDATA[<p>My intention this past week was to focus on my health and set myself up for success.<!--excerpt--> I followed through on this primarily by going to the doctor to get a letter to support taking a health-related leave of absence from work, starting in October. I also purchased and started the <a target="_blank" href="https://itsryannnicole.com/hfm">Hunger and Fullness Masterclass by Ryann Nicole</a>, a Licensed Professional Counselor (LPC) and Certified Nutritionist. Her podcast, The Food Freedom Lab, has helped me to realize that I still struggle to manage my emotions without food and listen to my body’s hunger and fullness cues. It can get frustrating and overwhelming to feel like I haven’t made progress because I’m still struggling with disordered eating, but I try to remind myself that seeking out help is already progress, and we just have to take it one day at a time. 
<br />
<br />
Another problem I could no longer ignore was the fact that the insoles I got to help me recover from plantar fasciitis are so thick that none of my shoes fit with them inside. Trying to motivate myself to run and walk was hard enough without shoes that hurt and cause blisters, so I resolved to get a new, larger pair of max cushion shoes. After watching several comparison videos and trying a couple brands and models, I settled on the ASICS Gel Nimbus 25. They’re heavenly–I can really feel the high squish factor when walking, but they also work for my easy runs (the only type of runs I do as I rebuild my aerobic base following the MAF method since I got covid at the end of May). I couldn’t resist the amazing cooler weather this weekend, so I walked 10 km Saturday and 11 km on Sunday without getting any blisters. I’m so excited to now have comfortable shoes for my first half marathon walk with two friends at the end of October!
<br />
<br />
Speaking of friends, I’m especially grateful for my friend who helped me get a government subsidy for my mental health prescriptions last week. I was not confident that there would be anyone in my local ward office who could speak English and help me, so my friend came to translate both the documents and interactions as I submitted my application. We both learned a lot about the process, and we emerged victorious with my application approved in under an hour. This was a scary life admin task I was dreading so much, and there’s no way I could have done it as quickly without such a generous and smart friend. 🥹🥹🥹
<br />
<br />
Last week wasn’t just wins though. I had my fair share of fails, but the one that keeps nagging at me is my “new” hairstyle. I went to the hair salon to get my hair bleached into an ombre look with dark brown roots that fade into blonde ends, but I left with low lights so low that my hair just looked exactly the same shade of brown overall as when I entered the salon. My hair dresser told me that the brown beige dye she put on top of the highlights she gave me would fade well, and I’d like the result in a week, but I was extremely disappointed. I really like this hairdresser as it’s rare to have someone who speaks English, but she totally missed the mark this time. I’ve been debating for days if I should ask to schedule another appointment to get the hair I actually wanted because this doesn’t come close to the reference images I sent her. I doubt I’ll grow the spine for something like that, so I’ll just stick with being a salty brunette for now.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-recap" /><category term="health" /><category term="reflection" /><category term="adulting" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My intention this past week was to focus on my health and set myself up for success.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weekly Recap: Sept 11 - 17</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/18/weekly-recap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weekly Recap: Sept 11 - 17" /><published>2023-09-18T21:51:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-09-18T21:51:00+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/18/weekly-recap</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/18/weekly-recap.html"><![CDATA[<p>I took two days off from work to visit Kyoto with my partner’s family because they found a great deal on a huge, newly renovated <a target="_blank" href="https://mykyotomachiya.com/kyomachiya/">kyomachiya</a> accommodation.<!--excerpt-->  It was pretty spectacular with exposed wood beams, recessed lighting, an outdoor garden, rotemburo (outdoor bath), and a sunken living room with a velvet couch that created such a lovely central hub to the home. However, Kyoto’s weather was horrifying with extreme heat, creating a real feel of 42C/107.6F in the sun. We were only there for two nights and one full day, so I brought along a parasol for some very sweaty cafe hopping. It was my third or fourth time in Kyoto, so there was no pressure to eat or see specific things. Every time I go there, I feel like there’s really not that much to see outside of the touristy spots during peak sakura or fall leaves, and the subway system is inconveniently limited. I don’t want to go back unless we get a really cool accommodation like this one again.
<br />
<br />
Despite only working three days, I was surprisingly stressed because I had to present at work for the first time in years. I facilitate large meetings weekly and have no problem speaking in those public settings, but this time was up in front of a podium. Even though my portion of the presentation was blessedly brief and went fine, I still left the office as soon as I could afterwards to decompress for the rest of the afternoon and evening at home. I vaguely recall a presentation I gave to a director at least four years ago, but I’m kind of shocked that I haven’t presented anything since then. My experience seems to back up the consensus of how working at a remote site will stall your career and decrease your visibility, but I can’t imagine working our of the headquarters and being a careerist again. I hate capitalism too much to sell my soul like that now. <br />
<br />
In some of my down time this week, I was able to create a light version of my layout and a theme switcher thanks to <a target="_blank" href="https://derekkedziora.com/blog/dark-mode-revisited">this extremely easy and straightforward tutorial</a>. The biggest pain was just changing my CSS to use a bunch of variables instead of specifying hex code values in line like I had before. I was surprised that two folks said dark mode was a strain on their eyes and that they thanked me for creating a light mode. I’ve always felt the opposite, but I’m happy that I can provide folks a more comfortable viewing experience now. I really want to create even more versions of my layout now that I have the capability. <br />
<br />
In other web-related news, I’m extremely excited about the launch of <a target="_blank" href="https://marigold.town/">marigold.town</a>, which is a project run by <a target="_blank" href="https://xandra.cc/">Alexandra</a>! I’ve already finished coding my submission to the town, and look forward to sharing it with you all soon.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-recap" /><category term="webmastery" /><category term="travel" /><category term="reflection" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I took two days off from work to visit Kyoto with my partner’s family because they found a great deal on a huge, newly renovated kyomachiya accommodation.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Static Blogging on The Small Web: Bear Blog</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/14/static-blogging-small-web.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Static Blogging on The Small Web: Bear Blog" /><published>2023-09-14T09:46:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-09-14T09:46:00+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/14/static-blogging-small-web</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/14/static-blogging-small-web.html"><![CDATA[<p>There are always aspects of my website that I want to improve, but they sit in the back of my mind and just yammer away, begging for attention until I eventually conduct all the proper rituals necessary to coax my mind into focusing. One of these neglected yammerings is my blog. <a href="/2022/11/06/blogging">My Obsidian &amp; Jekyll blogging setup</a> is still working well, yet <a target="_blank" href="https://bearblog.dev/">bear blog</a> calls to me.<!--excerpt--></p>
<ul>
  <li>It has a barebones <a target="_blank" href="https://bearblog.dev/discover/">discovery feed</a> with upvoting that makes it really easy to find and sort through interesting posts from all bear blogs. Given that Neocities’ follow feature is the reason I’m still active on Neocitites, I know that discoverability is essential to sustaining my own long-term participation in the small web, so I’m definitely drawn to a blogging solution that has more of that.</li>
  <li>It also provides built-in RSS feeds for all blogs, which has become quite important for me now that I’m happily set up with an instance of Fresh RSS that is generously provided by the amazing <a target="_blank" href="https://32bit.cafe/">32-bit cafe</a>, which you should join if you’re 18+ and want a fun, helpful, and SFW community across the small web. I’m quite disappointed by how few Neocities sites have RSS or atom feeds because I want to keep up with y’all and your blog posts!</li>
</ul>

<p>Despite commenting being a top requested feature, bear blog <a target="_blank" href="https://bear.nolt.io/9">won’t support it</a>, so I would still be struggling with that there. Currently, if anyone wants to interact with one of my posts, they can only do that through the Fediverse thanks to <a target="_blank" href="https://webmentions.neocities.org/">webmentions</a>. While I am extremely happy with my mastodon instance and have slowly developed a list of people to follow that make it an interesting place to return to daily, I know that many folks have found Fedi to be Not It for them for a variety of reasons. So, how can I enable commenting for folks who aren’t on Fedi?</p>
<ul>
  <li>I will never use Disqus because people on the internet tell me it’s a tracking nightmare and also slows down your site (<a target="_blank" href="https://renatello.com/wordpress-disqus-comments/#:~:text=Disqus%20cons,-Slow%20site%20speed&amp;text=It's%20a%20well%2Dknown%20fact,additional%20~2MB%20of%20absolute%20junk.">1</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://fatfrogmedia.com/delete-disqus-comments-wordpress/">2</a>).</li>
  <li>Work and my ADHD have made answering emails a dreadful chore that I need to be paid to do, so I don’t want to give out my email just to disappointingly leave a lovely soul on read if they care enough to write to me.</li>
  <li>I could try to figure out how to set up comments with <a target="_blank" href="https://staticman.net/">Staticman</a>, but Jekyll is something I barely understand as an amateur web dev hobbyist, so I don’t need to add an additional point of failure into the mix quite yet. 
If you think I should consider another solution for commenting for static sites, please get in touch. I apologize that I cannot accept messages via carrier pigeon nor smoke signals at this time.</li>
</ul>

<p>So will I move to bear blog? Not right now. I prefer my Obsidian writing experience that is bolstered with a <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/PKM-er/obsidian-editing-toolbar">rich text editing toolbar plugin</a> and built-in spell checker. To have the bear blog integrated within my site instead of pointing off to the bear blog site, I’m pretty sure I’d have to have a custom domain. While I’ve flirted with the idea of getting a domain for Lost Letters, I think it better supports the small web if I don’t remove neocities.org from my site’s URL to help promote it as a home for personal sites like mine.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reflection" /><category term="webmastery" /><category term="learning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are always aspects of my website that I want to improve, but they sit in the back of my mind and just yammer away, begging for attention until I eventually conduct all the proper rituals necessary to coax my mind into focusing. One of these neglected yammerings is my blog. My Obsidian &amp; Jekyll blogging setup is still working well, yet bear blog calls to me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weekly Recap: Sept 4 - 10</title><link href="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/10/weekly-recap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weekly Recap: Sept 4 - 10" /><published>2023-09-10T18:58:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-09-10T18:58:00+09:00</updated><id>https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/10/weekly-recap</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lostletters.neocities.org/2023/09/10/weekly-recap.html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite enduring yet another oppressively hot week in Tokyo, I was still able to further examine agency as a means of counteracting learned helplessness, learn more about CSS flex as I refreshed my site under the hood, and meet up with a new friend. <!--excerpt-->
<br />
<br />
<b>Learning about agency:</b> The revelation of learned helplessness is still rippling through my mind, but mostly in terms of its antithesis: agency. I’m seeing agency as a theme pop up everywhere in my life, even as I read through The Artists Way, an unnecessarily theistic (it’s honestly getting a bit repulsive for me) self-help book with legitimately beneficial exercises to help you unlock creativity. In an <a target="_blank" href="https://youtu.be/0wE8C-ErkcY?si=VlOuhYWJIhPRcz12">interview with Dr. Seligman</a>, Professor of Psychology in the University of Pennsylvania’s Department of Psychology as well as the former president of the American Psychological Association, he explained (starting around <a target="_blank" href="https://youtu.be/0wE8C-ErkcY?si=emLhAlJHKtFxW_Ne&amp;t=258">4:19</a>) that it doesn’t matter if you do or don’t have free-will, the key is that you <i>believe</i> you do. It’s such an uplifting message that no matter what you’re struggling with, the power lies within your perspective. From my own experience, I think the amazing thing about shifting perspective is that, unlike willpower, it has a long-term lasting impact with a lot less effort. This is something I’ve observed first-hand when I went vegan. I couldn’t unsee my new perspective on the animal agriculture industry even though I would love to go back to my blissfully ignorant past self. My life would be <i>so</i> much easier if I wasn’t vegan, but this perspective shift has been persistent despite no effort on my end to maintain it like watching vegan documentaries (I can’t bare to see animals hurt, so I don’t even watch those). One thing that bothers me about this so far is that this all seems a bit “pull yourself up by your bootstraps”, so I want to seek out BIPOC and disabled perspectives on this to understand and acknowledge the role that systems of oppression play within this paradigm. If you have any recommendations, please drop them in my guestbook or get in touch another way.
<br />
<br />
<b>Flex-ifying my layout:</b> Until now, my layout code was a real mess. When I decided to change my layout to the space-themed one you see now, I tweaked my old one instead of coding it from scratch, which is what I should have done. Using flex to structure my layout has been on my to-do list for what feels like months, and it ended up being much easier than expected! I did end up spending hours on it, but that’s just because I was trying to figure out a layout of my site that suited a three-column format. I couldn’t end up justifying prominence I was giving to the two sidebars’ content, so I ultimately decided to stick to my single column. Even if that didn’t materialize into anything, it’s definitely a confidence booster to know that I could code a three-column flex layout without issue if I ever end up wanting one. In the process of this, I also couldn’t help but move a couple things around. I’ve put my RSS icon next to my blog link in the navigation to give that more prominence. I also deleted my Now page that I just revamped this week, moving my “find me elsewhere” links into my footer. I also added my status cafe and latest blog post to the homepage, so it looks more lively. If something looks wonky despite my QA efforts, please let me know. One last thingI would be remiss if I didn’t thank <a target="_blank" href="https://pixelglade.net/resources/collections/onlineradio">pixelglade</a> for turning me on to this incredible, free site that allows you to finely tune high quality ambient soundscapes: <a target="_blank" href="https://mynoise.net/">myNoise®</a>. I spent quite a few hours coding to the Irish Coast one, finding it to be extremely effective for boosting my focus, so I wanted to share it in case it’s helpful to others.
<br />
<br />
<b>Meeting up with a new friend:</b> Right before I went to Europe, I attended a knitting meetup where I just happened to sit down next to a fascinating and helpful person whom I chatted to for three hours. We really hit it off, and I told her I was in search of interchangable Addi (brand) knitting needles. She serendipitously had two sets of them with accessories, which she offered to sell me for a steep discount of only $100 USD. This is a truly shockingly low price because just one set costs $159.95 USD, according to the <a target="_balnk" href="https://www.addiclicks.com/">Addi website</a>, not including the cord-stoppers ($14.95 USD) and extra cables used to connect the needles that she wanted to throw in for free. I had to jump on the deal as soon as I was back from Europe, so we finally met up post-trip to exchange the goods. While this could have been just a quick swap, she ended up buying me dinner (an incredible all vegan enchilada, which is a dish I haven’t had in more than four years!!!) and we easily talked for 5 hours! She also asked me in advance if there were any vegan American foods I wanted from the commissary on base, where she lives, which was so kind. I’ve been tearing my way through this hoard of all my dearly missed vegan foods that she got me, including Beyond Meat Sweet Italian Sausage and Mandarin Orange Crispy Chick’n by Gardein. It really made me wonder how much healthier of a relationship to food I would have if my options weren’t so annoyingly difficult and limited here.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="webmastery" /><category term="reflection" /><category term="fun" /><category term="learning" /><category term="food" /><category term="weekly-recap" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite enduring yet another oppressively hot week in Tokyo, I was still able to further examine agency as a means of counteracting learned helplessness, learn more about CSS flex as I refreshed my site under the hood, and meet up with a new friend.]]></summary></entry></feed>